e e
[Music]
thank you for that man you're quite
welcome can you hear me I feel like it's
not on you're not on I mean my button's
on now we hear you good okay talk with
authority all right I'm going to call
the finance committee meeting to order
um Mr wolfinger is probably somewhere
tropical so I
am taking his place so we're going to do
something a little different um we only
have one resolution tonight and a few
ordinances so resolution
1725 this
is bids for the new building at Engine
House 3 so I'm not going to read the
Preamble I'm just going to kick it right
to Mr Biz Jack as the sponsor uh thank
you Mr chair uh I mean you pretty much
adequately uh you adequately described
it right there once again this
legislation is authorizing the
administration and the SSD specifically
to go out for bids uh to build the uh
the new building here by Engine House 3
so that our firefighters have a you know
a shelter to actually store equipment
fix fire trucks what have you um so this
will be a phenomenal asset for our fire
department happy to share this money for
the building's already been set aside um
so once again this is just authorizing
the fire department to uh you know go
out to bid for a contract to build this
facility um so with that being said Mr
chair uh Mr Su will be my second and
this will be three readings all right
anyone have any other
questions you have anything Chief
sorry thank you very much uh yes this
legislation is just to allow the
department to go out um this is a No
Frills building no windows no air
conditioning just a place that I can s
my fire truck safety trailer um and a
location that's secure and we can
monitor it and it's um close enough for
us to switch out trucks whenever it's
needed so um
it's also a place for our firefighters
to to work on equipment if they need to
right now it's kind of inside outside
whatever they find the opportunity to do
that to do so so um we really appreciate
the
opportunity thank you Chief thank you
thank
you any other
resolutions like we're coming in okay uh
temporary or moving on to ordinances
temporary ordinance number
925 that is updates to sanitation
Department's ordinance Mr ALS yes I saw
Sean come in he's going to address the
issues good evening everyone um so this
is a kind of a two-piece it's a little
bit of cleaning up um what we accept at
the down at the transfer station and
then it's also getting a clarification
on as you know previously if we had for
a while where if um people would come
into the the transfer you could bring
yard waste in um we're not doing
anything to affect any of the curb side
that would still be totally as it is in
the ordinance it states you know
seasonal curb sides free um but we we
we're experiencing a sort of a festering
of of issues of having the uh yard waste
free there at the scales um a lot of um
you know hey give me your your
sanitation bill so or your utility bill
so I can go dump my yard waste from
wherever for free and that it it was
something that is really creating a
issue I call them the ambers we have
Amber and Amber Lin so I call them the
ambers and they were really getting into
a lot of uh sort of because they're the
gate Gatekeepers of that so they're
trying to make sure that we're um we're
we're taking in what we should be taking
in and and it's creating a lot of
Confrontation for them with people that
are unfortunately taking advantage and
and and kind of you know ruining that
process so the best way you know we're
still going to do it at curbside for
free so it's not punishing or penalizing
anybody but it would be um there would
be V gate fees um dumb fees associated
with brain yard waste into the transfer
station and Sean the fees are basically
the same as for taking any other kind of
debris to the exactly it's $30 for a
truck load
right it just basically says that that
that dump would mirror whatever the
current you know our current dump fees
are which is $30 for a minimum up to 999
pounds and $50 a ton PR rated after that
but the difference is there will be a
charge and you may hear about that
because there hasn't been a charge and I
just wanted to make sure that everyone
understood that and Sean and I talked
and the committee talked and we'd rather
protect the privilege the fact that
you're picking up yard waste at my curb
is a tremendous benefit that I don't
know that people really I don't know if
they value it or not I value it I I do a
lot of landscaping and it's important to
me I carried mine over to the transfer
station in my truck because I didn't
want to fill a 100 bags a week it's just
easier to throw it at the back of the
truck and take it over but now that it's
not free I'll be I'll be choosing Plan B
at the curb lots of bags at the curb and
that's unlimited as it always but I
appreciate that that's I i' I've lived
long enough there's the time in this
town when we didn't have that we had
nowhere to take it and no one was
picking it up so I appreciate it yeah
that's something that's I mean honestly
it's gotten really expensive to manage
it was sort of industrywide everybody
was was is like oh this is amazing we're
going to to yard waste composting but
it's it's been what what we
unfortunately what we bring in I've
tried many different Avenues to get rid
of um once it's once we've spent the
money and made the compost and
unfortunately there's so much trash and
other things in it that I've had three
or four different you know Ohio Mulch
two different Farmers that were coming
to get in loads and they just quit they
they can't take it so this way we can
also sort of you know watch that and and
with doing the gate fees then if I am
sending it out you know we have we have
a way mechanism that we're paying for
that tonnage that's leaving because
there's no when yard waste is created
there's actually no Revenue in any of
Sanitation funds that that pay for yard
waste it is just as it says it's when
when I base the rate and we did our
increases last year there's there's none
of that rate that actually granted it
gets spent because we we have to spend
the fuel and spend the time but there's
not a not a specific piece that that
that funds that that
item thank you Sean thank you anybody
have any
questions no thanks thank you uh
temporary ordinance
1025 uh piece for last piece for
annexation in Greenfield Township uh
Economic Development Committee Miss hoop
um yeah this is just the formal
acceptance of the um annexation along
Election House Road um it is one reading
it's my understanding it's because of
the deadline due to the type of
annexation is that correct so did you
have anything else to say I would just
add that um our pre-annexation agreement
requires us to do this as well so couple
of different reasons but just one
reading It's the final acceptance you
all had the the hearing the public
hearing at the last meeting um and if
you remember nobody came uh to speak in
opposition to that we do have um
Elizabeth with vor's here tonight to
speak to it if anybody has any questions
left but otherwise we'll just ask you
for suspension thanks
okay uh Mrs Kates is your second y yep
anybody have any questions on that no
okay thank
you uh ordinance
1125 this is a an easement uh for the
mayor
to authorize an easement for a through
water water pollution Mr Wing yes uh
thank you Mr skover um AE informed the
water department that uh the city has to
grant them an easement for them to be
able to do some uh Power work there at
the side of the new North Water
Treatment Plant and would like to invite
stevenh to come up and speak to it in a
little more
detail good evening Council uh thank you
councilman Wing as noted um this the
origin of this legislation is related to
the north water plant and again the um
very recent notification we received
from AP that they would require an
easement from us in order to put in the
power that's needed to run the plant um
I've sent the email to all of you
beforehand kind of giving you an outline
of the timing of that and the crunch we
would be under if this legislation did
Go full three readings hopefully you
thought that was well articulated and
answered a lot of your questions um
there are a couple of things I wanted to
add um in response so one a council
member inquired so I thought I would
clarify for everyone um on the timing we
did become aware of the need for this
easement on the Thursday before the
previous city council meeting but I was
not aware of the timing crunch we would
be under that information came in the
subsequent week after the previous
council meeting so it would not have
been possible to bring this legislation
before you at the previous council
meeting at least not without a bunch of
unknowns I I didn't want to come to
council and ask you to potentially
consider of spending when I didn't know
with certainty whether or not that would
be necessary so um that was kind of my
thought process there um one other thing
I'll add um subsequent to the uh version
of legislation I sent you yesterday um
law director Hall noted that um this was
lacking an emergency provision that
would allow us to get that easement
signed right away so we could get it to
AP and again get the ball rolling on on
getting this work done so she went ahead
and added uh some of that verbiage in
just again putting that emergency
provision in to allow us to um get that
signed right away and and like I said
keep that moving um so I thank her for
noticing that and getting that added in
otherwise if anybody has any questions
I'd be happy to uh try to answer
them no seeing none thank you very much
yeah thank you
all last ordinance we have for
introduction tonight is 1225 this
is for the Tiff uh in timbertop through
Economic Development Mrs
hoot um yeah I was hoping Stephanie
would be here but she's not so the
others Stephanie might have yeah no
problem so uh I actually let Stephanie
Bosco know she's the executive director
of the Port Authority um that she didn't
need to be here tonight um I explained
to the economic development committee um
we're in the process of working with she
and I both are in the process of working
with um Lancaster development company in
order to uh have the port authority
issue conduit bonds and in order to do
that the city has to enter into a new
Cooperative agreement uh for the
timbertop Tiff uh some of you will
remember most of you probably weren't
here for this but way back in 2021 um we
started the process of a tiff um at
timbertop and that's um tax increment
financing to fund public infrastructure
there um and back then the goal was to
just pay for the public infrastructure
um but now as you know costs are rising
and developers are having a hard time um
constructing their projects um the
lanter development company has asked
that uh the proceeds be split a
different way and they intend to issue
conduit bonds about four I think four
and a half five million um through the
Lancaster Port Authority and then the
funds will be split in another way in
order to make sure that those get paid
um
it at first we thought we would amend
the current Tiff Cooperative agreement
but then we realized that financially
that would be a nightmare because
somebody would have to do all of the
calculations under the old and then also
the amended agreements um so we have
agreed instead to just do a new Tiff
Cooperative agreement that spells
everything out and addresses all of the
you know changes and what's happened in
that development up to now so because
that is going to be a long and involved
document and we are kind of on a
deadline with regard to the bond
issuance obviously those things are you
know very regimented and have certain
requirements that you have to hit at
certain times um they needed us to go
ahead and start reading this legislation
even though we don't actually have the
draft documents in hand for you guys to
review so we were hoping once we got
those in hand we could come back and you
know do a better job of explaining and
describing um why you needed to do what
what we were asking per The Cooperative
agreement but for now just reading it
would be fantastic thank
you I figured there were going to be
questions so we can ask some questions
but I know and I know Mr wolfinger had a
list of questions so and then most of us
around the
table haven't had any experience with a
tiff so I know Stephanie is always
available for those explanations which
again she can do here but at the same
time this is why we like three readings
right because we are going to have
plenty of questions on this one why it
makes sense why it doesn't so go ahead
not a question about a tip I'm just
curious uh where Argus growth
Consultants fits into this so they are
we're we're required to have a third
party um review the the distributions
and all of the tax Collections and all
of that in order to make the investors
on the bond side comfortable so that's
what Argus growth does okay thank you
you're welcome Miss tener yes well back
when this happened in 2021 I actually
voted no on this project because
something just didn't seem right to me
um but how far are we in the process of
this because I remember when they came
and presented this to us they were going
to do this Assistant Living place and it
was going to create like hundreds of
jobs and then then they ended up if I
recall oh sorry I'm sure people can
still hear me without that on um so the
can't in there so oh so they um built I
think was it two stories and then they
wanted a three story right is that right
they but but I'm just kind of like what
are we doing I can't remember the whole
I think you're thinking of the multif
family development yes originally it was
two-story and then it became a three
story but you know how far are we in
this assisted living and the things they
talked that we supposed to go on First
and the project I remember that they had
presented that and then they're supposed
to create jobs how how are we doing with
the development of the property yeah so
the the one parcel the vision
development is already completed like
you said it was originally a two-story
multif family um residential development
and they turned it into a three-story
multif family residential development
they've been leasing that for at least
two years now um but vision is a
different developer than the original
developer and so they pay a service fee
per an agreement um the assisted living
facility that you're talking about is
under construction now and Lancaster
development company is working on that
um so I don't know how far along it is
in the process I apologize I don't know
if the mayor or SSD has got any updates
from the building department but I don't
know where they are in that process
however I do know they're 80% sorry done
and they will bring those jobs 221 so
that's what I was kind of so the other
part is they're also adding um uh senior
Villas so one story they supposed to
have done at the beginning yes yeah I it
might have got a little you know changed
around in terms of phasing um but at
this point they're working on the senior
Villas as well um and then there's also
uh plans for a multi family residential
development um behind the Villas uh by
it's another Vision development Vision
wants to I don't know where they are in
process of purchasing that property and
building there but they have committed
to another residential multi family uh
development at the same site so the
people that originally from Canton are
they out of it or they're still in no
they're the Lancaster development okay
because I know I remember there was a
different name for the lemon lemon so
what what developers do is for every
project they develop they typically open
an LLC at that site right so Lancaster
development company is what's developing
the assisted living facility I forget
what Vision calls their developments but
it's they're all owned by separate llc's
and that's just you know by design for
for the corporate
structure so Becky if I would uh for
everyone uh when this Tiff was
originally Becky's right on about the
promises made if you remember uh Co had
something to do with the Slowdown and
getting um getting that project moving
was during that same time frame so
everything that that was laid out to us
from Limon development is actually 2021
everything that was laying out laid out
to us by lmon development is actually
being built right now the Assisted
Living if you haven't been by it's a
beautiful looking Place uh from the
outside it looks complete but they're
working on the inside all the jobs that
were promised will be there because
they're going to have an assisted living
facility in Lancaster Ohio that's
desperately needed by an aging
population Who currently on waiting list
at every other place in the city so uh
we Willow we will be allowed to keep our
um older folks in Lancaster and not have
to send them to Columbus or Grove City
or uper rington for housing uh the
the uh Villas they're building are
envisioned as independent living with
the ability to transition to the
Assisted Living should should that be
necessary at some point uh and also part
of the Tiff
infrastructure has been requested by the
city we we want to build a road and
lemon part of their agreement was to
build this road all the way to the river
valley Highlands property line we
eventually would like to connect River
Valley Highlands with timbertop to allow
for and exit from River Valley Highlands
uh from the school area uh we think
that's desperately it's been planned for
so long but um these are all good
questions and your memory is correct
Becky it's it was a lot of promises made
sometimes development doesn't work as
quickly as we would like but 2021 really
was it the out coming out of the covid
thing so you know they still had supply
chain issues and money issues and
funding issues seem to be okay with it
but I'm just saying every project in the
pipeline is a 3 to four year project
none of them happen in in a short period
of
time any other questions I've got a
couple do we have any documentation that
shows what we've spent already on
infrastructure and um what kind of
revenues have been collected so far and
then maybe a time table of what will be
spent and what what we expect to come in
that'll all be part of the Tiff package
and you you'll be to see all that it'll
be okay thank
you any other
questions all right like I said first
reading will be tonight three readings
and then your second would be Mrs KES
yes sir yep okay that's all we have for
ordinances do we have any departmental
updates
Mr de and Mr
Schultz Just One update I just wanted
the noticed that at the next meeting I
didn't have time to get the legislation
ready for this meeting um but I will
have a couple of V Nows um for your
consideration thank you thank
you good evening I just want to give you
guys a little heads up I'll blip on your
radar as it may um cemetery's got uh
three projects we want to start to
complete this year one of them is a roof
replacement for the Moz l out Forest Ro
Cemetery one of them is to build a an
additional storage facility out at Maple
Grove Cemetery as well as pave some New
Roads we cut in out there this year or
last year um we've developed a new
section out there and the road is
required to get to it and right now it's
just a kind of a dirt road kind of a
thing so we want to get it paved um so
it can be in use matter of fact the
section we did developed uh started
selling right away and we just had our
first burial in it two weeks ago and due
to this condition we had to keep folks
on the existing roadway and they kind of
had to walk a little a little bit of a
distance with the snow and ice so we
want to get that taken care of in order
to in order to do that um we're going to
transfer some money from the Perpetual
care fund uh we met with the finance uh
or the investment committee today and uh
Treasurer Stoten who verified we have
the money the committee is good with the
move so next coun next uh meeting you'll
have some legislation in front of you
which can go three readings uh to move
those money that money around and get
appropriated into the cemetery expense
account where it needs to
go perfect thank
you any questions for him I just kicked
them away before I asked sorry sorry Tim
any other departmental
updates
no science meeting prep we have nothing
outside the ordinary all right
business any other items for this
meeting seeing none I'm take a motion to
adjourn
tojn and roll call is a yes right you're
a yes because you made the motion we're
adjourned the regular meeting of
Lancaster City Council will commence
promptly at 6:30
the Frankie Smith Funeral Home in
cremator in Lancaster and the Johnson
Smith Funeral Home in Baltimore have a
long and wonderful history of serving
our community feel free to give us a
call at
0652 stop in and see us at either of our
two locations 405 North Columbus Street
in lancas and 207 South Main Street in
Baltimore respect for tradition regard
for change
change great automotive service is just
around the corner at the Buckey family
of dealerships whether it's Buckeye
Nissan at hilard Georgesville Nissan at
the Georgesville Auto Mall Buckeye Honda
of Lancaster Buckeye Toyota of Lancaster
or Buckeye Collision Center in hilard
team Buckeye Services all mix and models
at each location utilizing modern
practices with hundreds of years of
experience giving you peace of mind
that's how we Buckeye
[Music]
e
e e
please rise if you are able and join me
in a moment of
prayer God grant us the serenity to
accept the things we cannot change the
courage to change the things we can and
finally the wisdom to know the
difference please join me in the Pledge
of
Allegiance I pledge aliance to the flag
of the United States of America and to
the republ for which it stands one
nation under God indivisible with liy
and justice for
all I now call the February 10th 20125
Lancaster City council meeting to
order please call the RO Mr Al here Mr
bisj here Mrs kites here Mrs hoop here
Mr lenberg here Mr skover here Mr suy
here miss tener here Mr Wing here let
the record reflect that nine members of
Lancaster or city council are present
this evening could I please have a
motion to excuse councilman wolfinger Mr
President I'd like to make that motion
we excuse Mr wolfinger second we have a
motion second to excuse council member
wolfinger all those in favor please
indicate by saying
I all those opposed same sign now we
will move on to the reading and
disposing of the journal regular meeting
minutes dated January 27
2025 Mr President I'd like to make a
motion to receive and file the journal
second we have a motion a second to
receive and file the journal all those
in favor please indicate by saying I I
all those oppose same sign we'll now
move to the reports of City officials
email datea January 31st 2025 regarding
dwater facility bids submitted by city
environmentals engineer um Denise Cruz
email dated January 31st 2025 regarding
2024 law director and City prosecutor
annual report submitted by law director
Hall email dat of February 9th regarding
update to Temporary ordinance
11-25 submitted by storm waterer manager
Steven wellstead email dated February
10th 2025 regarding January 25th income
tax report or January 2025 income tax
report submitted by Tax Commissioner
Hamilton email dated February 10th 2025
regarding um update the temporary
ordinance 1-25 submitted on by
stormwater manager Steven
wellstead Mr President I'd like to make
a motion to receive and file the reports
of City officials second we have a
motion and second to receive and file
the reports of City officials all those
in favor please indicate by saying I I
all those oppos same sign now move on to
the Communications email data January
31st 2025 regarding the request for
process to magn process or Magna on
obtained amounts owed to city of
Lancaster submitted by treasur of lanter
City Schools Julie
Taylor Mr President I'd like to make a
motion to receive and F the
communications second we have a motion
and second to receive and file the
communications all those in favor please
signify by saying I I all those oppose
same
sign special Awards or special
presentation and
awards there are none petitions and
memorials there are no petition or
memorials this evening at this time we
move to the permission of Voters and
taxpayers to address city council are
there any individuals here this evening
that wish to address city
council seeing none we thank you for
your attendance at tonight's
meeting we will now remove move to the
reports of standing committees finance
committee meeting minutes dated January
28 2025 submitted by Mr Wolf aner
finance committee agenda dated February
8th 2025 submitted by Mr wolfinger
treasury investment committee minutes
February 20 or 10th 2025 submitted by
law director Hall and I believe that's
it Mr President I like to make a motion
to receive and file the reports of
standing committees second we have a
motion second to receive and file the
reports of standing committees all those
in favor please signify by saying I I
all those oppose same sign
reports of special committees there are
no reports we have no public hearings
this evening which means we will now
move on to the reading of resolutions
beginning with the third reading of
temporary resolution
4-25 a resolution to appropriate from
the uncovered balance amend the
certificate of Appropriations with the
county auditor in the Wastewater
replacement and Improvement fund 6023
and authorized the issuance of then
announc certificate for payment of bills
water water pollution committee and Mr
Wing and Miss tener and council member
Wing thank you Mr President I moved um
Council pass and gross and enter upon
the written record temporary resolution
number 425 second we have a motion a
second to pass from gross and enter upon
the written record temporary resolution
425 any discussion council member wng uh
yes this is an annual piece for water
pollution control uh just moving money
into the 6023 fund for um various sewer
improvements thank you any further
discussion hearing none please call the
role Mr ALS yes Mr bisack yes Mrs K yes
Mrs hoop yes Mr lenberg yes Mr skover
yes Mr suy yes Miss tener yes and Mr
Wing yes temporary resolution 4-25
passes 99 to Z temporary resolution
5-25 a resolution to increase appropri
increased receipts appropriate from the
unincumbered balance and amend the
certificate of other sources with the
county auditor and the Wastewater
replacement and Improvement fund
6023 this is through water and water
pollution committee Mr Wing and Mr alss
council member Wing thank you Mr
President I move to the council pass and
gross and enter upon the written record
uh temporary resolution number
5-25 second we have a motion second to
pass and gross and enter upon the
written record temporary resolution
5-25 discussion council member Wing yes
this is another annual piece and it is
um a budgeted fund to fund transfer into
the same fund thank you any further
discussion hearing none please call the
RO Mr alss yes Mr bjack yes Mrs kites
yes Mrs hoop yes Mr lenberg yes Mr
skover yes Mr suy yes Miss tener yes and
Mr Wing yes temporary resolution 5-25
passes 9 to0 temporary resolution
6-25 a resolution to amend the
certificate of Appropriations with the
county auditor appropriate from the
unincumbered balance increase receipts
and complete a fund transfer in the
Wastewater fund
6004 and in the Wastewater utility
Reserve Reserve fund
6029 again this is water water pollution
committee and Mr Wing and Miss tener
council member Wing uh Mr President I I
move the council pass and grow center
upon the ri record resolution temporar
number 6-25 second we have a motion and
second to pass and gross and enter upon
the written record temporary resolution
6-25 uh discussion council member Wing
yes our final annual piece of the
evening uh this is a $2 million transfer
in order to be uh compliant with the
bond Bond covenants thank you any
further
discussion hearing none please call the
role Mr ALS yes Mr bisj yes Mrs KES yes
Mrs hoop yes
Excuse me yes Mr lenberg yes Mr skover
yes Mr Su yes Miss tener yes Mr Wing yes
temporary resolution 6-25 passes 9 to Z
we now move on to Temporary resolution
7-25 a resolution to amend 2025
appropriation budgets and amend the
certificate of Appropriations with the
county auditor this is through finance
committee
um member skover yeah Mr skover Mr Su
council member scon over Mr President
I'd like to make a motion that Council
pass Andross and enter upon the written
record temporary resolution
725 second we have a motion a second to
pass and gross and enter upon the
written record temporary resolution
725 council member
over I don't have any comment thank you
any further discussion hearing none
please call the RO Mr alss yes Mr bisack
yes Mrs KES yes Mrs hoop yes Mr lenberg
yes Mr skover yes Mr suy yes Miss tener
yes and Mr Wing yes temporary resolution
7-25 passes 9 to0 that concludes our uh
third readings of resolutions and we now
move on to Second readings uh beginning
with temporary resolution
11-25 a resolution to appropriate from
the unencumbered balance and amend the
certificate of Appropriations with the
county auditor in the police and fire
Levy fund
2047 this is through Safety Committee Mr
bizjack and Mr Sully council member
bizjack thank you Mr President this will
be the second of three readings second
of three readings on temporary
resolution
11-25 temporary resolution
12-25 a resolution to authorize the
service safety director to enter into an
agreement with the Ohio Department of
Transportation to purchase rock salt for
the 2025 d 2026 winter season this is
through Public Works committee Miss
Tiner and Mrs crates council member
Tiner second three readings second of
three readings on temporary resolution
12-25 temporary resolution
13-25 a resolution to authorize the
service safety director to advertise for
bids and enter into contracts for the
purchase of chemicals for use by the
division of water this is through water
water pollution committee Mr Wing and Mr
ALS
council member Wing second of three
readings second of three readings on
temporary resolution
1325 temporary resolution
1425 a resolution to authorize the
service safety director to advertise for
bids and enter into contracts for the
purchase of pipes and fittings for use
by the division of water this is through
water water pollution committee Mr Wing
and Mr Miss tener council member Wing
second of three readings second of three
readings on temporary resolution
1425 thought you said you had the three
and you were done this evening yeah yeah
three annual pieces uhuh okay we go
started here we go all right we now move
to the temporary resolution
1525 a resolution to authorize the
service safety director to enter into a
contract for construction of the solids
handling replacement project again this
is through water water pollution
committee Mr Wing and Mr alss council
member Wing uh Mr President I'd like to
to make a motion that Council suspend
its rules and wave uh the third reading
of temporary resolution
15-25 second we have a motion in a
second to suspend the rules and wave the
third reading of temporary resolution
1525 any discussion council member Wing
uh yes we talked a lot about the solids
handling replacement project at the last
council meeting and the reason for
suspension is the loan paper work is due
on the 15th thank you any further
discussion on the motion to suspend
hearing please call the RO Mr ALS yes Mr
bisj yes Mrs K yes Mrs hoop yes Mr
lenberg yes Mr scov yes Mr Su yes Miss
tener yes and Mr Wing yes motion to
suspend uh temporary resolution
1525 passes 9 to zero council member
Wing yes Mr President I'd like to make a
motion that Council um pass and gr enter
upon the written record uh temporary
resolution number
15-25 second we have a motion a second
to pass and gross and enter upon the
written record temporary resolution 1525
any further discussion nothing further
hearing none please call the RO Mr ALS
yes Mr bisack yes Mrs K yes Mrs hoop yes
Mr lenberg yes Mr skover yes Mr tally
yes Mr suy Sorry Miss tener yes and Mr
Wing yes motion to pass and gross and
enter upon the written record temporary
resolution 1525 passes 9 to0 temporary
resolution 16
14-25 Okay resolution to move existing
budget between accounts appropriate from
the unincumbered balance and amend the
certificate of Appropriations from the
county auditor in the storm water sewer
fund
6006 this is through finance committee
Mr skover and Mr
alss me second of three readings please
second of three readings on temporary
resolution
1625 we will now move on to the first
reading of resolutions begin with
temporary resolution
17-25 a resolution authorizing the
service safety director to advertise for
bids and entering a into a contract for
the construction of a maintenance and
storage facility for use by the
Lancaster fire department and to declare
an emergency this is through Safety
Committee Mr bisj and Mr Sul council
member bisj thank you Mr President this
will be the first three readings first
of three readings on temporary
resolution
17-25 that concludes our reading of
resolutions we will now move on to the
reading of ordinances beginning with the
third reading of temporary ordinance
1-25 an ordinance to accept the final
plot for the Fairfield Park development
this is through code enforcement and
zoning committee miss Mr suy and Mrs
hoop council member suy thank you Mr
President I move that Council pass and
engross and enter upon the written
record that ordinance uh temporarily
numbered uh
125 I second 1-25
sorry second second we have motion a
second to pass and gross and enter upon
the written record temporary ordinance
1-25 any discussion council member
soling I think we've covered this at the
last few meetings so no additional
discussion thank you any any other
discussion hearing none please call the
RO Mr alss yes Mr bisj yes Mrs crates
yes Mrs hoop yes Mr lenberg yes Mr
skover yes Mr suy yes Miss tener yes Mr
Wing
yes motion to pass and gross and enter
upon the written record temporary
ordinance 1-25 passes 9 to0 temporary
resolution
3-25 in ordinance to repeal Lan are
codified ordinance part seven business
reg Regulation Code chapter 711 715 721
731 785 and 791 of the codified
ordinances of the city of Lancaster this
is through law committee Mrs Kites and
Mr bisj council member KES yes thank you
Mr President i' would like to make a
motion that Council pass and gross and
enter upon the written record ordinance
temporarily number
3-2 second we have a motion in a second
to pass engross and enter upon the
written record temporary ordinance
3-25 I need discussion council member
cres yes thank you um this is to repeal
unneeded and obsolute
portions of part seven in the business
code uh there sections that were passed
between the 1950s and 1980s that are
impacted they involve business types
that no longer exist in the city or no
longer need enforcement because of
existing laws would one of those be an
arcade was it arcades and yes okay yeah
I don't think we've had video game
arcades for a while so all right
um any further
discussion hearing none please call Mr
ALS yes Mr bisj yes Mrs cres yes Mrs
hoop yes Mr luberg yes Mr skover yes Mr
suy yes Miss tener yes and Mr way yes
temporary ordinance 3-25 passes 9 to Z
we now move on to Second reading of
ordinances beginning with temporary
ordinance
7-25 an ordinance to authorize the mayor
to enter into a school compensation
agreement for income tax sharing between
Lancaster City School District in the
city of Lancaster and to declare an
emergency this is through finance
committee Mr Wolf or I'm sorry Mr skover
and Mr Sul council member scoon over a
second of three readings please second
of three readings on temporary ordinance
7-25 temporary ordinance
8-25 an ordinance to amend permanent
ordinance 51-24 the management pay
ordinance and to declare an emergency
this is through administrative Services
committee Mr lenberg and and Mr wolfing
or was your second council member
council member lenberg thank you Mr
President this is second of three
readings second of three readings on
temporary ordinance
8-25 um we'll move on to First readings
beginning with temporary ordinance
9-25
sorry an ordinance to repeal and replace
Lancaster codified ordinance part nine
streets utilities and public service
code chapter 937 was removal this is
through service committee Mr ALS and Mrs
hoop council member ALS first of three
readings please first of three readings
on temporary ordinance
9-25 temporary ordinance
10-25 and ordinance to accept the
annexation of
22.0 plus or minus acres in Greenfield
Township and to declare an emergency
this is through Economic Development
Committee Mrs hoop and Mrs crates
council member hoop yes Mr President I
would like to make a motion that Council
suspend its rules and wave the second
and third reading of temporary ordinance
1025 second we have a motion in a second
to suspend the rules in way of the
second and third reading of temporary
ordinance
10-25 uh any discussion council member
hoop um no thank you any further
discussion hearing none please call the
RO Mr alss yes Mr bisack yes Mrs C yes
Mrs hoop yes Mr lenberg yes Mr skover
yes Mr Su yes yes Miss tener yes Mr Wing
yes motion to suspend the rules and wave
the second third reading of temporary
ordinance 10-25 passes 9 to zero council
member hoop thank you Mr President I
would like to make a motion that Council
pass engross and enter upon the written
record temporary resolution or ordinance
10-25 second we have a motion second to
pass Andross and enter upon the written
record temporary ordinance
10-25 any discussion council member hoop
no um I would just note once again uh
for those who may not have been here we
had a public hearing on this particular
annexation last week and there was
nobody who spoke in opposition U please
call the role Mr ALS yes Mr bisack yes
Mrs KES yes Mrs hoop yes Mr lenberg yes
Mr skover yes Mr Su yes Miss tener yes
Mr Wing yes temporary ordinance 10-25
passes 9 to0 temporary ordinance 11-25
an ordinance authorizing the mayor to
Grant a permanent easement to the Ohio
power company necessary for the
construction of electric facilities to
serve the North Water Treatment Plant
and to declare an emergency this is
through water water pollution committee
Mr Wing and Mr alss Mr Wing is back yes
Mr President i' like to make a motion
that Council suspend its rules and weigh
the second third reading of temporary
ordinance number
11-25 second we have a motion and second
to suspend the rules and the second
third reading of temporary ordinance
11-25 any further discussion uh we
discussed this in finance I mean the
only thing I would stress is that a has
stressed that they won't start the work
until they're granted the easement thank
you any further discussion hearing none
please call the RO Mr ALS yes Mr bisack
yes Mrs crates yes Mrs hoop yes Mr
lenberg yes Mr skover yes Mr Sol yes
Miss tener yes Mr Wing yes motion to
suspend the rules and wave the second
third reading of temporary ordinance
11-25 passes 9 to0 council member Wing
Mr President I'd like to make a motion
that uh Council pass and gross and enter
upon the written record a temporary
ordinance number
11-25 second we have a motion a second
to pass and gross and enter upon the
written record temporary ordinance
11-25 any further discussion nothing
further thank you please call the RO Mr
alss yes Mr bjack yes M Mrs Kates yes
Mrs hoop yes Mr lenberg yes Mr SC over
yes Mr Sully yes Miss tener yes and Mr
Wing
yes temporary ordinance
11-25 passes 9 to0 temporary ordinance
12-25 an ordinance authorizing the
execution and delivery of a of a
Cooperative agreement among the
Lancaster Port Authority the city of
Lancaster Ohio Lancaster development
company l C and the Huntington National
Bank and authorizing the appropriation
of tax
increment uh financing funds for payment
of debt service with respect to a
maximum aggregate principal amount of $6
million of Port Authority revenue bonds
to be issued to pay costs of public
infrastructure improvements authorizing
the execution and delivery of a tiff
Administration agreement between The
Argus growth Consultants l ldt in the
city authorizing and approving related
matters and declaring an emergency um
this is your Economic Development
Committee Mrs hoop and Mrs crates
council member hoop yes this is just
first of three readings first of three
readings on temporary ordinance
12-25 that was a lot for get do twice
two more times I know exactly um but
that was a lot
all right uh that concludes our reading
of ordinances uh this evening uh we do
have a piece of tabled legislation and I
do look to the law director again we're
still waiting on that correct all right
thank you so um we now move to
unfinished business is there any
unfinished business uh of any council
members this evening I would just note
that we have had some discussion and
you've seen it on the council floor and
there's been some folks indicate that
it's council's preference that we read
legislation three times I want to make
it clear that that is the law um
exceptions are only made in instances in
which we have compelling reasons on a
legal basis or a financial basis to move
legislation forward with a uh one with
fewer than three readings so just want
to make that clear for everybody um new
business are is there any new Council
council member tener hand up on new
business I'll think the see what year is
this okay this is the second one time I
think I've spoken this year so far um I
just think I mean we do the you know we
the tree City USA and all this and you
know they talk about the thousand tree
planting where's that going to be what
what I mean that is people have just
you've got to clarify that because I
just that was a number okay well I just
because I'm like I don't I'm thinking
faor asked us for a dream and I said I
want to plant a th frees a year just I'm
glad that's out there was listening oh
people were listening believe me people
listen to things that
aren't people listen to things that
aren't true and Becky listens no well
they were telling me and I was like
there's no way we could be doing that
anyway I do think though since we are
Tree City USA and that and we haven't
done this for years I know they sold the
equipment years ago I think it's a big
burden on a lot of the homeowners I
really do think we need to have the leaf
pickup again I understand we have the uh
you know putting them in the bag and all
that a lot of people can't do that and
it is very very costly for a lot of
residents to find somebody to come and
get their leaves um some people don't
even have trees and they get neighbors
leaves and but I do think it's something
we really need to look at to come bring
that program back again to pick up
leaves at the curbs there's a lot of
cities that still do it 20 years ago and
I I just think it needs to be a
discussion we need to have okay Becky I
never never thought I'd ever say this
but I totally agree with you oh my gosh
what you you've witnessed a first this
evening
a I've also heard from one of my you may
want to wait and find out the cost
before you totally agree well there's so
many different and that and we have the
tree commission we have all kinds of
different maybe we can get a grant for
the you know we would most likely have
to contract it out we don't have the
equipment and when that was done before
every Department participated
we can't do that any longer
um it it would we can certainly explore
a cost if council's pleasure to look at
that but it's not as easy as saying we'
like a program back that was disc
discontinued about 20 years ago because
of cost well I I just think it needs to
be maybe we need to reach out to some of
these cities that are doing it and see
how they're going about it because there
and you know I would think too because I
know when I drive around and it's
raining out I'll get out and I'll take
take um my garbage bag out and I'll see
there's leaves in a in a drain and it's
not allowing the water to go I mean it
should help the water department I mean
it should help flow and not get so much
debris in because we know we have that
street sweeper that goes around and
kicks up stuff every I participated in
the program it was very beneficial as an
individual homeowner um I certainly see
the value on the homeowner side uh we
can certainly explore the cost but I
think it's going to probably be
significant thank you Mr Mayor thank you
council member tener thank you council
member ALS for agreeing with council
member Tiner for the first time in write
as many years we will write that down oh
it'll be okay in minutes it'll be in the
minutes any further new
business thank you uh we will now move
on to the announcement of scheduled
meetings February 24th 6:30 p.m. here in
council chambers and then again March
10th 2025 um at 6:30 p.m. in council
chambers so those are regularly
scheduled City Council meetings any
special scheduled meetings there are
none regularly scheduled committee
meetings Okay up upcoming committee
meetings um are for economic develop um
I apologize finance committee February
24th at 6 PM in council chambers law
committee um was scheduled for February
14th but is to be rescheduled and the
time and date is to be announced um code
enforcement February 20th at 7:30 over
in City Hall
1897 and uh service committee March 7th
at 8:00 a.m. and City Hall 1897
conference room and Public Works
committee March 14th at 7:30 a.m. in
City Hall 1897 room thank you greeting
of
bills um we have one for $13.87
apolog 13083 I apologize MCO mnco yes
okay thank you Mr President I'd like to
make a motion we pay the bill I'll
second we have a motion second to pay
the bill all those in favor please
signify by saying I I all those oppose
same sign we have no need for an
executive session therefore I will now
take a motion to adjourn Mr President I
would like to make that motion we
adjourn second have a motion a second to
adjourn all those in favor please
signify by saying I I all those oppose
same sign thank you this evening's
meeting is adjourned if you have
legislation please be sure to sign
before you leave thank
you excuse me
[Music]
e for